Now, let's revise that implementation and see before moving and do that exercises and see how to implement
and how to create a stack and chart.
So the stack implementation included, as did the IO and acidity level that etch and define MAX 10 and
count equal to zero.
Now, to create this stack, we have to create a struct called stack.
It contains two things the item array and having a maximum element as max and we have an event called
top end with typedef struct stack SD.
We have created now to create empty stack as the contains SD and stack that that is defined as throughout
this application as SD.
And we will create as to the top equal minus one because we are creating an empty stack.
Now the third thing is creating jack of the stack is full and is full.
It is a method that returns and.
And it took into perimeter is tracked note gold struct there, a structure of type S3, which is a stack
and check if the top as the equal max minus one, it will return one, otherwise it will return zero.
So this is how would check if their stack is full now to check if the stack is empty, we create a method
in the same way.
It's called is empty asthe took into perimeter is structured fast and as equal equal to minus one,
it will return one.
Otherwise, it will return zero.
So if that top equal equal to minus one, then the top integer it refers there is no elements inside
the stack.
OK.
Adding elements interest stack, if this has this operation is called pushing void push, we have seen
this, but it is more a general method here took into parameter to the that you are going to push elements
inside it and then you add them as and that you are going to be pushed.
So it is full recheck.
If there's a stack of full Brent F. stack fully else, it will remove that will move that up to their
necks and increase it by one.
And as items as at top end stop it equal to then you might remember we are creating the stack using
the AC and increased count by one removing element from the stack.
We take into perimeter the stack that we are going to be it to be performing and removing elements from
it and the check if it is empty, we can't remove anything.
So print stack as empty.
Otherwise, it will print the item that that this popped and decrease the top element by one and decrease
the count and print f.
Then, Brent, elements of the stack really have seen it in the previous video, how to move the cursor
and how to create also a loop that loops all through all the elements of the array and print items.
OK.
And we see how to test this implementation, the stack and boom implementation in a main method using
the stack here.
So we are creating the empty stack, reserving the memory and pushing S1 as as do, so we are pushing.
So first of all, we have named the stack as s and we are inserting inside this as number one, number
two, number three and four.
No printing the stack, you can print the stack and you check it on the C compiler and pop.
So we are popping the elements and the printing.
After popping out, we print the stack again.
We will take into that into consideration.
That one is inserted at the first two, up three after and four at the top.
So if we are popping, we are removing no fault from it.
Please try to implement this code in your C compiler and in the next videos.
We are going to solve the exercises using the Java in the same way.
How to implement the stack in Java using the array.